Contact No: 919999084052 e-mail: jvidhi14@gmail.com

Nominated Corporate Counsel, Global Awards-Lex Falcon

Senior Legal Counsel with a demonstrated history of working in corporate commercial legal advisory for over 15 years with focus on heightening productivity. Strong record of contributions in negotiating India, APAC, US and other geography high value contracts, due diligence and integrations on M&A's, data privacy, ESG assessment, intellectual property rights, litigation, regulatory, compliance and ethics management.

Key Achievements:

- Managed legal functions of 13 entities amalgamated and acquired under one parent company
- ➤ Drafting, vetting, negotiating and advising on transactions and agreements vis-à-vis IT, SAAS, MSA, SLA, Advertising, Content, Media, Services, Real Estate, FMCG, Supply-chain, e-commerce, Data Protection. Reviewed approx. 5000 contracts till date.
- Developing and managing contract templates and related documents according to changes of laws and regulatory framework and organizational changes in processes and business priorities.
- ➤ Handling IPR Portfolio to enhance Brand Reputation, protected more than 1000 trademarks, applied and obtained patent for Virtual Reality device developed by nation's top automobile company.
- Managing litigations pan India mostly under NI Act, Consumer Matters, NCLT, Arbitration.
- Providing legal advice and support on legal and compliance matters for India operations
- Identifying legal issues, providing solutions and mitigation plan to minimise risks
- Working with APAC and Global legal team on projects and initiatives.
- Legal advice and opinion on new laws and amendments and their impact on business
- Leveraging new technologies and platforms to enhance productivity and reduce costs-Practice League, Salesforce, Docusign
- Jurisdiction: India, Singapore, Thailand, Phillipines, Vietnam, China, USA, UK

Work Experience:

> Senior Manager-Legal- MedGenome Labs Limited

Jun, 2023 till date

- Due diligence on Mergers & Acquisitions, reviewing essential requirements, deal structure in M&A's, integrations etc
- Advising on data privacy, data protection and other IT policies
- Drafting and ensuring compliance with internal policies of the Company
- Working on ESG compliance of the company,
- Overlooking contract lifecycle management
- Liasing with external counsels for litigation, IPR matters,
- Ensuring compliance with legal and regulatory requirements, employment laws
- Approving standard templates as per ICMR guidelines, PCPNDT Act and other applicable laws, Handling team of legal associates

> Senior Manager-Legal and Compliance - More Retail Private Limited

(Formerly part of Aditya Birla Group, now under Amazon)

Apr, 2021 till Feb, 2023

- Reviewed and negotiated Service Agreements, Lease Deeds, MSA, Vendor Agreements, MOU, NDA, SOW, Indemnity Bonds, bank guarantee and various other agreements/legal drafts
- Drafted template agreements, standard terms, legal notices and its replies
- Advised on FSSA, LMA, Weights and Measurements, labelling requirements
- Supporting compliance team in regulatory filings
- Brand strategist -Analysed IPR portfolio of the Company having more than 1000 trademarks including cease and desist notices, trademark applications, prosecutions, opposition, filing evidence, counter statements, domain name disputes, appearing before the Intellectual Property Appellate Board, Trademarks Registry and other concerned courts.
- Liasing and co-ordinating with external counsel on litigation and in Arbitration matters
 Member of IC (Sexual Harassment) and Code of Conduct Committee of the Company
- Trained internal teams on Ethics, POSH and other policies.

Senior Legal Counsel-JLL India (Jones LaSang LaSalle Inc.)

May, 2017 to Dec, 2020

- Advised on FDI, FEMA, Foreign exchange implications on existing and new business models
- Vetted, drafted, negotiated and finalized multi-million value agreements related to Real Estate
 Consultancy like Project Management Agreements, Design & Build Agreements, Lease
 Agreements, Property Maintenance Agreements, Valuations Contract, RFP's, SLA's, Leave &
 License Agreements in domestic and international geographies.
- Provided training on significant contractual clauses, data protection, privacy and IPR issues
- Worked with internal counsels from other geographies including APAC, US, UK.
- Advised on HR & labour compliances with updates on the applicable laws including Industrial Disputes Act, Contract Labour Act, Payment of Wages Act, Shops & Establishment Act.
- Ensured compliance to internal policies and procedures, Ethics & Compliance, Code of Conduct, Anti-bribery & corruption
- Co-ordinated with external counsels for litigation matters including on commercial contract disputes, NCLT matters, NI Act, legal recoveries, other civil and criminal actions
- · Cross functional communication with internal stakeholders and liaising with clients
- Identifying and mitigating risk, ensuring compliance with internal policies and legal/statutory requirements under stringent timelines
- Worked closely and effectively with senior management to understand their needs
- Collaborated with compliance team to develop framework and monitored compliance with laws

Asst. Mgr.-Legal -Paytm (One97 Communication Ltd)

Feb, 2014 to Apr, 2017

- Contract management through drafting, vetting and negotiating all kinds of contracts
- Handled matters under Negotiable Instruments Act, Arbitration cases, Winding up petitions, criminal complaints, labour cases etc.
- Litigation Management at PAN India level to ensure speedy closure of cases.
- Legal support to HR, Admin, IT and Supply Chain.
- Ensured legal compliance & due diligence within the organisation under Shops & Establishment Act, Labour Welfare, anti-bribery
- Trademark filings and oppositions proceedings.
- Updated and maintained MIS of Company legal data.

Legal and Corporate Practice

Anand & Anand Excel Law Group

Jan, 2010 to Jan, 2014

- Drafted legal pleadings, legal notices, legal opinions, conducted legal research.
- Appeared before High Court, District Courts, Tribunals and Consumer Forums in civil and criminal matters.
- Drafted and reviewed contractual documents pertaining to NDA, Assignment Agreements, Joint Venture Agreements
- Drafted, reviewed and negotiated broad range of commercial contracts pertaining to supplier, vendor, production, confidentiality contracts, lease deeds, sale deeds, rent agreements, settlement agreements and other property related documents.
- Reviewed & prepared property verification reports by investigating title/ conducting due diligence.
- Hon'ble Mr. Justice S.N. Dhingra, Retd. Judge, Delhi High Court Hon'ble Mr. Justice Manmohan Singh, Judge, Delhi High Court Law Researcher
 - Intensive legal research on various subjects of law including Contract Act, IPR, civil laws, criminal laws, Limitation Act, Property Act.
 - Prepared brief memoranda on the cases reserved for judgment.
 - Case summarization with issues involved and interpretation of various laws involved.

Internship:

- **Hon'ble Mr. Justice D.P.Wadhwa**, Retd. Judge Supreme Court of India (May, 07 to June, 07)
- Mr. K.C. Mittal, President, Delhi High Court Bar Association (May, 2006 to June, 2006)

Academic Credentials:

- ➤ [2023]-PGDIPR-National Law School of India University Bangalore-Pursuing
- > [2022]-Certificate course Labour&Industrial Laws (MSME Technology Development Centre)
- > [2021]-Certification in Cyber Laws (Linkedin online)
- ▶ [2007]-Bachelor of Laws from Campus Law Centre, Delhi University 1st Div.
- ➤ [2004]-Bachelor of Commerce from Jesus & Mary College, Delhi University, 10th Rank holder in the Delhi University,

Other Skills:

- ➤ Proficient in Microsoft applications: MS-Office, Powerpoint, Excel
- Expertise in legal research softwares: Manupatra, Lawpack, Supreme Court Cases (SCC), Westlaw, Lexis Nexis, Delhi Law Times (DLT) etc.